

Aranganathan Rathinavelu

FULLSTACK ENGINEER

Eindhoven, North Brabant, Netherlands

[(+31) 644249247 | ■ hello@aranga.in | 😭 aranga.in | 🖸 arangates | 🛅 arangates

Summary

Currently Frontend Engineer at start-up company Boloo. 5+ years experience specializing in the Frontend development building quality, user-friendly and high-performance web experiences.

Skills

Programming JavaScript, Typescript, Node.js, Python, LaTeX

Front-end React, Redux, HTML5, SASS, NextJS, TailwindCSS, Webpack, SEO

Back-end Django, DRF, REST API, Redis, Celery **DevOps** Linux, AWS, Docker, Gitlab CI/CD

Work Experience

Boloo B.V Eindhoven, Netherlands

FULLSTACK ENGINEER Aug. 2020 - Present

- Improved accessibility by implementing Theming(Dark mode), internalization.
- Deployed a Error monitoring environment(Sentry) which gathers Frontend Errors.
- · Implemented Complete redesign of User facing dashboard using customized Ant design system.
- Integrated ESLint, prettier and Git hooks for maintaining consistent code base.
- Completely responsible for delivering 3 projects(Internal dashboard, Email campaign, Invoicing).
- · Responsible for building new components, Involved in code reviews, Project planning and deployments.

Reverence Technologies sp. z o.o

Warsaw, Masovian District, Poland

FULLSTACK ENGINEER Nov. 2019 - May. 2020

- Developed frontend features using React, Redux, SSR.
- Developed minor backend features using Python, Django, DRF.
- Wrote Cypress E2E tests which covers complete functionalities.
- Built Order Book visualization, Time series graph using chart.js.
- Overlooked infrastructure, developed and administered Linux deployment and operations solutions using Gitlab CI/CD , Docker, Nginx.

FRONTEND DEVELOPER Aug. 2018 - Nov. 2019

- Managed Front-end using React, Redux, styled-components.
- Implemented a client-side localization system for the entire app.
- Did Performance optimization and was fully responsible for shipping code to production.
- · Migrated from client side to server side rendering (SSR) which improved SEO score significantly.
- · Eliminated Bootstrap and other CSS libraries completely from the application, and replaced them with custom styled-components.

FRONTEND DEVELOPER Nov. 2017 - Aug. 2018

- Did a major re-engineering of the development workflow which led to increase in development speed.
- Responsible for making bug-fixes in existing web application.
- Used Angular,RxJS,Ngx-Bootstrap,HTML 5,CSS 3.

Anulom Technologies Pvt Ltd

Coimbatore, Tamil Nadu, India

Aug. 2017 - Nov. 2017

FRONTEND DEVELOPER(CONTRACT)

- Implemented AWS S3 storage support for the application.
- · Successfully delivered a mobile application in two month time.
- Developed an Hybrid Application from scratch using Angular 4, Ionic 3.0.

ExamlyBengaluru, Karnataka, India

FRONTEND DEVELOPER

• Managed Front-end using Bootstrap, Angular 2, Typescript, HTML5, CSS3.

- Developed Hybrid mobile application from scratch using Ionic framework.
- Introduced and enforced a consistent coding style across the application.
- Crafted a solid design system to enforce consistency across the application.

Jun. 2016 - Jul. 2017

Education

Anna University Tamil Nadu,India

B.E. IN ELECTRICAL AND ELECTRONICS ENGINEERING

May. 2012 - May. 2016

• Learned, researched in the field of Internet of Things, Embedded Systems and Robotics. Actively participated in various IoT Sprint Hackathons.

• Principal subjects: Engineering Mathematics, Embedded Systems, OOPS, Data structures, Algorithms, C, C++.

Program Committees

2016	Problem Writer, 2016 CODEGATE Hacking Competition World Final	S.Korea
2013	Organizer & Co-director, 1st POSTECH Hackathon	S.Korea
2012	Staff, 7th Hacking Camp	S.Korea
2012	Problem Writer, 1st Hoseo University Teenager Hacking Competition	S.Korea
2012	Staff & Problem Writer, JFF(Just for Fun) Hacking Competition	S.Korea